Ryan Michael Williams

Full Stack Web Developer - San Francisco, CA

E-Mail: <u>ryanmichaelwilliams@gmail.com</u> | Phone: 954-593-9457 homepage: <u>http://ryanmichaelwilliams.com</u>

I have been making websites professionally since 2007. I'm currently interested in developing responsive designs through an MVC architecture with continuous deployment, embracing the latest innovations with HTML5, CSS3 and releated technologies. I enjoy working with a motivated team and also independently.

Technologies

ASP.NET; ASP.NET MVC; C#; VB.NET; Entity Framework; T-SQL; JavaScript; jQuery; CSS; HTML5; Nhibernate; Visual Studio 2012; SQL Server 2012; Windows Server 2012; Adobe Photoshop; Adobe Premiere; Mercurial; TeamCity;

Recent Relevant Experience

Mouthguard Store

Web Developer, Webmaster | TELECOMMUTE; JULY 2012 - PRESENT

Developed an E-Commerce solution for a variety of dental products. Integrated with PayPal checkout and set up AdWords campaign to track conversions. Project was made with ASP.NET 4.5 in C# with SQL Server 2012, NuGet Packages, jQuery, jQuery UI, Amazon S3, Windows Server 2012 and features a responsive mobile layout. Site uses SEO best practices such as rich snippets, video SEO sitemap, on page semantics and more.

Lvnton Web/ Nestlé

Technical Lead Developer | TELECOMMUTE; JANUARY 2012 - AUGUST 2012 (CONTRACT) Worked on a team with a total of 3 developers to build an intranet site that allows users in various roles to upload and evaluate videos and PDFs. Project was 100% telecommute and utilized Team City, Mercurial, Fluent Nhibernate, ASP.NET 4.0, SQL Server 2008 and C#. Content was stored in an Amazon S3 bucket with a server virtually hosted also in Amazon. Site was fully localized into 3 languages. Given the short term of the contract, was responsible for seeing the project through to completion as other developers left near the end.

Das Klub

Web Developer, Webmaster | SAN FRANCISCO, CALIFORNIA; AUGUST 2011 - PRESENT Independently built a responsive design social networking site for the industrial music industry using ASP.NET 4.5 MVC 4/ SQL Server 2012. Developed features include: Membership, Facebookesque Status Updates, User Filtering, Ajax Messaging, SignalR Chatroom, Twitter Bootstrap Layout, jQuery, jQuery UI, Google Maps, YouTube HTML5 API, Amazon S3 Video Hosting, Localization in more than 12 Languages with browser detection and a large array of smaller features and detail. Built a marketing campaign through viral YouTube videos, Facebook and Google advertising which quickly put the site on the map to the industrial music community in an unprecedented 2 months. The site is an international music community which assists in cross promotions with artists and has nearly 2000 user accounts.

JAR Media

Software Engineer | SAN FRANCISCO, CALIFORNIA; JUNE 2009 - SEPTEMBER 2011 Worked with company members and developer partners to understand business objectives and independently build a custom CMS template engine for creating high traffic webpages aimed at lead generation and credit card sales for the affiliate marketing industry. Integration with a large array of credit card processing APIs which successfully charged in excess of 700,000 transactions, captured

over 3.5 million leads and generated over 300,000 customers. Automated programs for processing customer records, real-time lead posting to external partners and secure batch credit card processing. The application primarily utilized ASP.NET Web Forms in C# and Windows Services on a load balanced Windows 2008 R2 web farm. In addition to the programming, was also involved in media buying campaigns and system maintenance. Received large bonuses for outstanding results.

Jocks Quarters

Web Developer | ORLANDO, FLORIDA; FEBRUARY 2009 - JUNE 2009

Lead developer for an ASP.NET C# Web Application utilizing Web Forms for the sports industry. Involved in database design, SQL Stored Procedures, OOP Design, user interface and control code using Telerik, class libraries, and HTML/ CSS. Created account management section, user profiles, registration system and search engine.

Pioneer Technology Group

Web Developer | SANFORD, FL; AUGUST 2008 - FEBRUARY 2009

Built a web application in ASP.NET Visual Basic for the real estate industry with the capabilities of importing records, indexing documents, managing customers, themes, permissions, e-mailing, user document uploading and marketing list generation from data imported and collected in SQL Server. Additionally, I worked on feature and defect requests for an online tourist tax development application.

Celebrity Resorts

Software Developer I | ORLANDO, FL; APRIL 2008 – JULY 2008

Consulted with high ranking company members, configured and deployed SharePoint 2007 (MOSS) intranet to replace existing intranet. Deployed a variety of MOSS features for hundreds users. Coded ASP.NET Visual Basic applications for internal use; converted some from PHP. Integrated company wide Active Directory with SharePoint.

Legends Investment Group

Web Developer Intern | CASSELBERRY, FL; DECEMBER 2007 – MARCH 2008 Worked with a small team of developers and designers to create a small business website system. Small businesses paid through their phone bill to have a website that showed their location and operating hours. The site also allowed the business to change their info. Coded in Visual Basic with ASP.NET 2.0.

Aptitude Solutions

Web Developer Intern | ORLANDO, FL; SEPTEMBER 2007 – NOVEMER 2007 Assisted in redeveloping the company website with SubSonic CMS. Made modifications to the website with Visual Basic, HTML and CSS.

Education

University of Central Florida (2007)

- BSBA: Management Information Systems
- BSBA: Marketing